grapefruit sucks by itself that's why as
a kid I would split one in half pile 100
grams of sugar on top get a spoon and go
to town ironically this is also how much
sugar is in a store-bought sorbet in
2023 there is no need for that so today
we are making three sorbets that have
about a hundred calories apiece and are
extremely simple to make let's get into
it we will start with a high sided
container and add it to a scale then add
230 grams freshly rinsed raspberries 210
grams water 40 grams urethra tall and a
half gram of salt of course you can use
the sweetener of your choice but try to
pick the freshest raspberries you can
having fresh raspberries will help
reduce the amount of sweetener you need
to add and will give you an overall
better tasting sorbet I tried this with
both 20 and 30 grams of erythritol and
it was still a bit sour for my personal
preference if you like yours a bit more
on the tart side I recommend trying
these out first then grab an immersion
blender and mix for 90 seconds we want
to make sure the raspberries are
completely crushed and the sweeteners
completely dissolved grab a pint and a
strainer and strain the mixture into the
Pint by doing this you will be able to
control how many seeds go into the Pint
keeping all the seeds in made for a more
chewy and less enjoyable sorbet my
favorite thing to do is either
completely omit them or use about half
of them the trick is to keep them spread
throughout the middle two-thirds of the
Pint the blade of the creamy will crush
them up into small pieces still giving
the sorbet a nice texture while being
able to enjoy the fiber benefits that
raspberries are literally loaded with
put the top on and add it to your
freezer full of creamy Pines 24 hours
later grab the Pint wash it under hot
water for one minute dry it off and load
it into the creamy hit that sorbet
button and after finishing this is what
we are looking like after the first spin
it definitely needs a re-spin so load it
back up and let the creamy do its thing
sometimes the sorbet will be ready to go
at this point but sometimes it needs an
extra re-spin like this example does
here if it does send it back through and
then enjoy your raspberry sorbet with a
thick almost cream-like texture without
any of the guilt for the next sorbet we
will need a large bowl a high sided
container and a microplane most recipes
benefit greatly from a little bit of
added zest and a grapefruit sorbet is no
different using our microplane we will
zest half of a large grapefruit directly
into the high sided container cut the
grapefruit in half and squeeze as much
juice as you can out of it into the
large bowl as you can see there is still
a ton of Pulp and juice that we can get
out of here so I will grab a spoon and
go around the grapefruit trying to get
as much out as I can without adding any
of the white part or what is technically
called the pith or Albedo of the fruit
this is very bitter and in early test I
tried peeling the grapefruit and getting
as much of the pith off as I could but
even just a little bit ruined the taste
of the sorbet this may be a little bit
of work but it's worth it what I love
about grapefruit is that it only has 33
calories per 100 grams which is listed
in an easy to read table format in my
cookbook along with all other fruits I
also have calorie tables for both meats
and vegetables along with 120 other
recipes that gets updated with all new
recipes I release if you want recipes
like my protein potato buns before
anyone else click the link in the pin
comment and use code e4cm for 10 off now
grab a strainer place it over the high
sided container and pour the grapefruit
juice there is perfectly good pulp
sitting in the strainer that we need to
add and we also need to make sure we
discard any seeds or packets of skin
like this once 220 grams are added
follow up with 220 grams of water 50
grams of erythritol and a half gram of
salt using an immersion blender mix for
90 seconds and add it to a pint you may
notice that as the grapefruit sits it
separates into different layers the top
layer will be more sour and the bottom
layer more sweet personally I love this
flavor contrast as I eat through the
Pint but if you want a more even flavor
throughout you will have to add your dry
ingredients separately to do this add
your erythritol salt and a half gram of
xanthan gum to a small bowl and mix then
while the immersion blender is running
slowly add the dry mixture until fully
mixed in and blend for an additional 90
seconds the xanthang gum will make sure
the grapefruit stays suspended equally
throughout the mixture as it sits and
freezes speaking of which freeze your
pint for 24 hours and when it's time to
eat rinse it dry it and add it to the
creamy hit the sorbet function and
re-spin one to two more times for
desired consistency the calories in this
or lack thereof is stupid and it's a
no-brainer for anyone wanting a
guilt-free tree my personal favorite out
of the three starts with some fresh
juicy Peaches I mean who doesn't love a
thick juicy Peach
[Music]
foreign after a thorough rinse take a
knife make a cut in the middle of the
peach and go around the entire pit twist
the two halves of the peach and remove
the pit add the peach to our high sided
container and repeat until we reach 300
grams I will note that you could use
either yellow peaches or white peaches
but in the testing process the white
peaches absolutely shine I would highly
recommend them if you can get some
quality white peaches at your local
grocer we will follow up the peaches
with 140 grams water 30 grams of urethra
tall and a half gram of salt it is time
to grab our handy dandy immersion
blender and once all of the peaches are
crushed continue mixing for 90 seconds
add the sweet peach mix to a pint and
freeze for 24 hours when hunger strikes
grab the Pint rinse the outside for one
minute and load it up mix it on the
sorbet function followed by the respin
function and repeat until desired
consistency is reached this sorbet is
perfectly peachy and can be enjoyed on a
daily basis without reaching Peach
fatigue while these flavors are great
you may have a hankering for some
strawberries or cantaloupe that's why in
this video here I covered three other
fruits so you have the most variety
possible making your diet way more fun
and sustainable until next time deuces